ALI SANAKNAKI

COMPUTER SCIENTIST

HTTPS://SANAKNAKI.GITHUB.IO
HTTPS://LINKEDIN.COM/IN/ALISANAKNAKI
HTTPS://DRIBBBLE.COM/THEGOOGLEINTERN
HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/SANAKNAKI
SANAKNAKI.ALI@GMAIL.COM

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer | SpottedU

JULY 2015 - APRIL 2016

Assisted in stress testing, bug fixing, planning and implementation of future app features. Using HTML, multiple CSS frameworks, and basic Javascript.

Social Media Lead | SpottedU

JULY 2015 - APRIL 2016

Advertised the startup platform using Facebook advertising tools, as well as utilizing Medium as a developer blog, and Buffer to queue posts for all social media accounts.

Web Content Specialist | ECCA

JULY 2016 - AUGUST 2016

Created and updated web pages for Environment and Climate Change Canada's MetPlus website using HTML and utilizing CSS classes under WET4 framework. Assisted in QA testing of features on the website.

PROJECTS

Cloutstagram

SEPTEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

Redesigned Instagram's mobile app interface, using Swift 4 and Firebase.

- Built the UI not using Storyboard, only Swift code.
- Utilized auto-layout to fit all screen sizes.

Jobify

MARCH 2017 - MAY 2017

Project for a Databases course for students to rate their co-op jobs, built using Rails, JQuery, and PostgreSQL.

- Designed the entire front end of the website.
- Implemented more features than the project required.
- Managed tasks between 3 other group members.

PROFILE

In search to gain work experience in my field of study, to be placed in a position that will give me the opportunity to implement and enhance my skills gained from my university courses, and to learn how to function and work in a group environment to meet specific goals.

EDUCATION

University Of Ottawa

Major: Honours BSc of Science in

Computer Science

Graduation Date: April 2019

SKILLS

Design: Sketch Photoshop

Languages: HTML CSS JS Java Swift

Social: Great at communicating with others regarding development processes and testing. Open-minded to criticism or ideas from peers or coworkers.

Other: Firebase Github